dayoneapp.com 2019-09-26

# Privacy Policy - Day One

The Day One app and its accompanying services are designed to maintain the private nature of your personal journal. This privacy policy outlines what information is collected and stored by Day One.

Bloom Built, Inc. (“​ **Bloom Built** ​,” “​ **we** ​,” “​ **us** ​,” or “​ **our** ​”) operates the Day One application and related websites (each, an “​ **App** ​” or a “​ **Site** ​”, respectively) and several related services (all such services, “Services”). Through our App and Services, we offer you a journaling program to record your memories, and, if you wish, share them with others as well.

## What Information We Collect and How We Use It

In the course of using the Sites and Services, we collect both personal and anonymous information. “​ **Personal Information** ​” in this Privacy Policy refers to information that allows someone to identify or contact you. Examples of Personal Information include your name, address, telephone number, e-mail address, as well as any other non-public information about you that is associated with or linked to any of the foregoing information. “​ **Anonymous Information** ​” is information not associated with or inherently linked to your Personal Information. Anonymous Information does not enable identification of or contact with individual persons.

### Personal Information

We will use your Personal Information to:

  * Provide you with Services and customer support;
  * Market our products and services to you that we believe may be of interest to you;
  * Respond to your requests, resolve disputes and/or troubleshoot problems;
  * Improve the quality of the Sites and the Services; and
  * Communicate with you about the Sites and the Services.

We may also use your Personal Information to create Anonymous Information records by excluding information that makes the information personally identifiable to you.

We will communicate with you primarily in the form of push alerts and emails. You can manage the frequency and/or opt out of receiving these communications by changing your settings on the App and/or clicking the “Unsubscribe” link at the bottom of each email. Please note that even if you unsubscribe or opt-out, we may still send you Site and Services related communications (e.g., emails related to your account or the App).

We collect the following types of Personal Information:

**Device Information:** When you download the App, we may collect your device type, your wireless carrier, and your individual device ID and we associate this with your Personal Information, though we primarily use this information to support your account and provide you with Services.

**Account Information:** To use our Services, you must register through the App with our Services and open an “Account” with us by providing your name, email address, and a password. We retain information on your behalf, such as entries, pages and messages that you store using your Account.

**Journal Information:** The most important thing we store is your journals. By default, your journals are private. Individual entries may be shared (see “Published Entries” below).

**Published Entries:** Day One provides a service, called Publish, that enables users to handpick selected entries to share. Our display of published entries is subject to the privacy settings you establish for them. When you publish or share content (text, images, photographs, messages, comments or any other kind of content that is not your e-mail address) as part of our Services, other users may be able to see it, including anonymous visitors to the Site. Please remember this and be thoughtful about what you publish.

**Transactional Information:** When you order Services through our App, we may collect information necessary to complete and record the transaction, though some of this information may go directly to our payment provider. If you tell us where you are (e.g., by allowing your mobile device to send us your location when you publish), we may collect, store and use that information. If you want to deactivate this feature, you can either reinstall the App(s) or deactivate location services on your mobile device. Of course, your location may also be apparent from your entries.

**Other Information:** We collect your other Personal Information that you submit to us voluntarily as you use our App, Site and Services. If you provide us feedback or contact us via e-mail, we will collect your name and e-mail address, as well as any other content included in the e-mail, in order to send you a reply. You can choose not to provide us with certain information, but this may limit the features of the Services you are able to use.

**Location Information:** In some cases we may collect and store information about where you are located, such as by converting your IP address into a rough geolocation or by accessing your mobile device’s GPS coordinates or coarse location if you enable location services on your device. We may use location information to improve and personalize our Services for you. If you do not want us to collect location information, you may disable that feature on your mobile device.

**Social Media Platforms:** Day One’s Services may include publicly accessible blogs, community forums, or private messaging features. The Site and our other Services may also contain links and interactive features with various social media platforms (e.g., widgets). If you already use these platforms, their cookies may be set on your device when using our Site or other Services. You should be aware that Personal Information which you voluntarily include and transmit online in a publicly accessible blog, chat room, social media platform or otherwise online, or that you share in an open forum may be viewed and used by others without any restrictions. We are unable to control such uses of your information when interacting with a social media platform, and by using such services you assume the risk that the Personal Information provided by you may be viewed and used by third parties for any number of purposes.

**Third-Party Payment Processing:** We may sell subscriptions or merchandise through our Services. When you make purchases through the Services, we process your payments through a third party application, including the Apple App Store, Google Play App Store, Amazon App Store (together with any similar applications, “App Stores”), Social Networking Sites (“SNS”) such as Facebook, and other third-party payment processers, including Stripe. The third party application may collect certain financial information from you to process a payment on behalf of Day One, including your name, email address, address and other billing information.

### Apple HealthKit

We never use your Apple HealthKit data for advertising and similar services or for use-based data mining. We don’t disclose information gained through Apple HealthKit to a third party or sell it to advertising platforms, data brokers, or information resellers.

### Anonymous Information

We will use your Anonymous Information to:

  * Keep track of logins and personalize your experience (including by tailoring content to you)
  * Enhance the Sites or Services
  * Improve the content of our software
  * Customize the App, Sites or Services to you
  * Contact you and/or market our products and services to you on our Sites or through our Services

We collect the following types of Anonymous Information:

**Information Collected by Our Servers:** To make our Site and Services more useful to you, our servers (which may be hosted by a third party service provider) collect information from you, including your browser type, operating system, Internet Protocol (“IP”) address (a number that is automatically assigned to your computer when you use the Internet, which may vary from session to session), domain name, and/or a date/time stamp for your visit.

**Log Files:** As is true of most websites, we gather certain information automatically and store it in log files. This information includes IP addresses, browser type, Internet service provider (“ISP”), referring/exit pages, operating system, date/time stamp, and clickstream data. We use this information to analyze trends, administer the Site, track users’ movements around the Site, gather demographic information about our user base as a whole, and better tailor our Services to our users’ needs. For example, some of the information may be collected so that when you visit the Site or the Services again, it will recognize you and the information could then be used to serve advertisements and other information appropriate to your interests. Except as noted in this Privacy Policy, we do not link this automatically-collected data to Personal Information.

**Cookies:** Like many online services, we use cookies to collect information. “Cookies” are small pieces of information that a website sends to your computer’s hard drive while you are viewing the website. We may use both session Cookies (which expire once you close your web browser) and persistent Cookies (which stay on your computer until you delete them) to provide you with a more personal and interactive experience on our Site. This type of information is collected to make the Site more useful to you and to tailor the experience with us to meet your special interests and needs.

We use Google Analytics to help analyze how users use the Site. Google Analytics uses Cookies to collect information such as how often users visit the Site, what pages they visit, and what other sites they used prior to coming to the Site. We use the information we get from Google Analytics only to improve our Site and Services. Google Analytics collects only the IP address assigned to you on the date you visit the Site, rather than your name or other Personal Information. We do not combine the information generated through the use of Google Analytics with your Personal Information. Although Google Analytics plants a persistent Cookie on your web browser to identify you as a unique user the next time you visit the Site, the Cookie cannot be used by anyone but Google. Google’s ability to use and share information collected by Google Analytics about your visits to the Site is restricted by the Google Analytics Terms of Use and the Google Privacy Policy.

**Mobile Services:** We may also collect non-personal information from your mobile device if you have downloaded our App(s) to your mobile device. This information is generally used to help us deliver the most relevant information to you. Examples of information that may be collected and used include your geographic location, how you use the App(s), and information about the type of device you use. In addition, in the event our App(s) crash on your mobile device, we will receive information about your mobile device model software version and device carrier, which allows us to identify and fix bugs and otherwise improve the performance of our App(s). This information is sent to us as aggregated information and is not traceable to any individual and cannot be used to identify an individual.

### Combining Anonymous and Personal Information:

We may combine any of the foregoing Anonymous Information with your Personal Information, in which case we will consider it to be Personal Information under this Privacy Policy.

## How We Disclose Information

### Personal Information

We also disclose certain Personal Information:

  * To third party vendors who help us provide the Services or the Sites;
  * To third parties to whom you ask us to send Personal Information;
  * To a parent company, any subsidiaries, joint ventures, or other companies under a common control (collectively, “Affiliates”), in which case we will require our Affiliates to honor this Privacy Policy;
  * In connection with or during negotiation of any merger, financing, acquisition or dissolution, transaction or proceeding involving sale, transfer, divestiture, or disclosure of all or a portion of our business or assets.
  * In the event of an insolvency, bankruptcy, or receivership, Personal Information may also be transferred as a business asset. If another company acquires our company, business, or assets, that company will possess the Personal Information collected by us and will assume the rights and obligations regarding your Personal Information as described in this Privacy Policy.
  * If we believe in good faith that such disclosure is necessary to (a) resolve disputes, investigate problems, or enforce our Terms of Service; (b) comply with relevant laws or to respond to requests from law enforcement or other government officials relating to investigations or alleged illegal activity, in which case we can (and you authorize us to) disclose Personal Information without subpoenas or warrants served on us; or (c) protect and defend our rights or property or the rights and property of you or third parties.

If you publish certain of your content, it will be made publicly available. This means that anyone may see it on the Site along with certain of your related profile information. Please be thoughtful about the entries you publish. In addition, our Apps and Services may enable you to post content to SNSs (e.g., Facebook or Twitter). If you choose to do this, we will provide information to such SNSs in accordance with your elections. You acknowledge and agree that you are solely responsible for your use of those websites and that it is your responsibility to review the terms of use and privacy policy of the third party provider of such SNSs. We will not be responsible or liable for: (i) the availability or accuracy of such SNSs; (ii) the content, products or services on or availability of such SNSs; or (iii) your use of any such SNSs.

### Anonymous Information

We reserve the right to disclose Anonymous Information publicly without restriction.

## Controlling Your Information / Request For Removal

You can review and/or change certain of your Personal Information by logging into the Site or the App and accessing your account. You authorize us to use and disclose any new or modified information that you provide in accordance with this Privacy Policy.

You can stop all collection of information by the App(s) by uninstalling the App(s). You may use the standard uninstall processes as may be available as part of your mobile device or via the mobile application marketplace or network.

You can access and modify the Personal Information associated with your Account through your Account settings. If you want us to delete your Personal Information and your Account, please contact us at [support@dayoneapp.com](mailto:support@dayoneapp.com) with your request. We will start the process to delete your information in a reasonable time.

## Information Disclosed to Third Parties

This Privacy Policy addresses only our use and disclosure of information we collect from and/or about you on the Sites and Services. If you disclose information to others, the use and disclosure restrictions contained in this Privacy Policy will not apply to any third party. We do not control the privacy policies of third parties, and you are subject to the privacy policies of those third parties where applicable.

The Sites may contain content or links to other websites that are not owned or controlled by us. We have no control over, do not review and are not responsible for the privacy policies of or content displayed on such other websites. When you click on such a link, you will leave our Site and go to another site. During this process, another entity may collect Personal Information or Anonymous Information from you. The Site may also contain links to other websites controlled by us but which operates under different privacy policies. Please review the privacy policy of any new site you visit.

## Child Usage Restrictions

Our Services and App are not directed to children and children are not eligible to use our Services. Protecting the privacy of children is very important to us. We do not collect or maintain Personal Information from people we actually know are under 13 years of age, and no part of our App or Services is designed to attract people under 13 years of age. If we later learn that a user is under 13 years of age, we will take steps to remove that user’s Personal Information from our databases and to prevent the user from utilizing the Sites and the Services.

**A Note to Users Outside of the United States.** If you are a non U.S. user of the App or Services, by visiting the Site and/or providing us with information, you acknowledge and agree that your Personal Information may be processed for the purposes identified in the Privacy Policy. In addition, your Personal Information may be processed in the country in which it was collected and in other countries, including the United States, where laws regarding processing of Personal Information may be less stringent than the laws in your country. By providing your information, you consent to such transfer.

## Changes to this Privacy Policy

This Privacy Policy is subject to revision from time to time on a going-forward basis. We will post any revised version of the Privacy Policy on this page. If we make any material changes to it, we will also send you notice to the last email address you have provided to us. Continued use of our Services following notice of such changes will indicate your acknowledgement of such changes and agreement to be bound by the terms and conditions of such changes.

## Questions about the Privacy Policy

If you have any questions or concerns or complaints about our Privacy Policy or our information collection or processing practices, or if you want to report any security violations to us, please contact us at [support@dayoneapp.com](mailto:support@dayoneapp.com) or at Bloom Built, Inc., Attention: Chief Executive Officer, 240 North 1200 East Suite 204, Lehi, Utah 84043.

This Policy was last revised: July 25, 2019.
